Hey, what's going on guys? Welcome back to another tutorial. In this one,
we are gonna go over how to edit a voiceover. Um,
and whether that's one that's recorded by your own team, or I'm sorry, uh,
recorded by an actor or recorded by a professional or recorded by herself.
Um, in this, in this scenario, I'm gonna,
I actually recorded one myself and we're going to,
I'm gonna show you some shortcuts that I use to optimize voiceovers
so that they're clean and fast and up to speed.
'cause I think the, one of the,
the biggest problems with voiceovers is when you don't trim them enough,
they kind of lag and they eat up a lot of time.
So I'm gonna show you how to do that right now. So,
going back to our project here,
I'm just gonna create a new sequence just so
it's nice and clean for us. So I'll do nine by 16 voiceover
and let's drag and drop the,
go to my S F X.
This is my voiceover. Alright, great. Just drag it in like that.
And this medically. So what I wanna do,
basically when starting off is I obviously wanna find the best takes, right? So,
uh,
that's the first thing I'm gonna do and I'm gonna be doing a lot of different
cuts. So, uh, one thing that you can do to already kind of anticipate,
you can increase your wave forms, increase the size here,
so you can kind of see where the gaps are. So immediately right there, I mean,
you know, that's gonna be dead space. So you can just cut that there.
This medically customized,
this medically customized metabolic weight loss program by new image is helping
transform the health of thousands of Americans. Okay, great.
That's a very long line, but obviously this is where it got cut off.
So I wanna just trim that, delete that, don't need it. This medical,
and I remember it being over here, it's,
so anytime you hear the, you wanna trim that,
so this is where that breath happens. Trim that, get that out of the way.
Get this, trim it up. It's called weightless. Okay,
let's isolate this less.
Let's trim this as well. Delete that.
A weight loss pro program, a weight loss treatment plan,
a weight loss treatment plan that consists of three,
a weight loss treatment plan that consists of three in one custom compounded
medications, diet plans,
and nutritionist support all through our digital health platform. Okay,
mouthful. Their lawyers went through this script, they really cut it up, so
it is what it is. So I'm deleting all that extra. I'm gonna go over here,
just make some extra space and hit w to bring down the
spacing here. Weight loss treatment plan, that considerations,
diet plans and nutritionist support all through our digital health platform.
So what I, what can do is, is delete some of this dead space right here,
or breathe in kind of necessary medications,
diet plans,
system, compounded medications, diet plans,
and nutritionist support all through our digital support.
Don't worry about the popping sounds. We'll get to that later.
Support all through our digital health platform. Boom. Cut there.
In a, in a, in a recent internal patient study in,
in a recent internal patient survey conducted by new image patients who took
weightless loss, an average of 17.8 pounds in their first 30 days.
Okay, boom. Cut there. Okay,
so I think this is dead. This is dead. I need to make some more space here.
In a recent internal patient survey, conduct image, patients who took
Space
By new image patients who took wait list, lost weightless,
is a prescription only weight loss treatment plan developed by some of the top
physicians and pharmacists. All right, cool. See,
all we're doing guys in this initial cut is
finding the actual usable takes, right?
And then trimming any of the, the fat,
any of the dead space wait list is a prescription only pharmacist.
And it isn't a, it's very,
very important to trim the dead space as close as possible,
especially for social media ads.
Like there cannot be any breathing room and it isn't available at your to,
and it isn't, and it isn't available at your typical local,
typical local or brand name pharmacy.
And it isn't available at your local or brand name pharmacy to see if, wait,
And,
And it isn't available at, like,
do you see the difference in that versus that?
And it isn't available at your local or brand name pharmacy to see if wait list
is right for you. Visit new image medical and see if you qualify.
All
Right? If medically appropriate, you can receive your medication in the mail.
If a medic, if medically appropriate, you can receive your,
if medically appropriate,
you can receive your medication in the mail in as little as 48 hours
begin. Okay?
Looks
Like you got a lot of trash here. If medically appropriate,
you can receive your medication in the mail in as little as 48 hours.
Begin your transformation today. Wait list by new image.
Every scale's best friend.
All right, begin your transformation today. Wait list by new image.
Every scale's best friend. Okay.
Cheesy of a pickup line, ending line there, but, okay,
so now that we've got all of our usable takes here, we've cleaned it up next,
what I'd like to do is really optimize this,
this flow here. Okay?
So one thing that I do not recommend doing is just linking up the clips
like this in a limi linear format like that. Don't do that. Okay?
What you wanna do instead is actually, um,
create like two layers and this medically customized
metabolic. What you wanna do is actually,
Lemme just move this up here so we can get more clear of the view.
Take these clips and stack 'em on top of each other, kind of like this. Okay?
Americans, it's called American.
What you're gonna get is like slightly of an overlap,
and this can control the pacing.
So there's no dead space whatsoever of thousands of
Americans. It's called weightless. You see that,
and I can bring this guy down underneath here, Americans,
it's called weightless,
a weight loss treatment plan that consists of three in one custom compounded
medications. See the difference there, we're,
we're really trying to optimize every little second in breath occasions,
diet plans and nutritionist support all through our digital health platform.
So this, the, the energy keeps flowing, there's no drop.
See, like instead of, you can get very precise when you,
when you move the clip like that versus cutting it entirely health platform.
In a recent internal patient survey conducted by new image patients who took
weightless loss, an average of 17.8 pounds. Okay,
we'll just continue this until you obviously like,
hear it for yourself. If it's too much of a blend,
their first 30 days wait list is like, that might be too close.
Days wait list is a almost like, as he's, as they're finishing the,
the previous line, like start the, start the next,
their first 30 days wait list is a prescription only weight loss treatment plan,
Pharmacist. And it isn't available at your local or brand name pharmacy,
Name pharmacy to see if weightless is right for you.
Name pharmacy to see if, wait, pharmacy,
to see if wait list is right for you.
Visit new image medical and see if you qualify, if medically appropriate,
you can receive your medication in the mail in as little as 48 hours.
Okay? Eight hours. Begin your transformation today. Wait list by new image.
Every scale's best friend. Okay, great. So
wait list by new image. I don't think I need this line at the end,
but what you're gonna see by doing something like this, all right,
is you're gonna actually shave off a few, like,
maybe a couple seconds at most from the video,
which actually makes a big difference. Um,
and the video itself is just gonna keep moving, moving, moving,
moving versus anytime there's a little gap, you know,
it's an opportunity for someone to, to just swipe through and lose attention.
So I like to keep things extremely tight and by new image is helping transform
the, and it, you know, you're, you have a higher chance of,
of sustaining their attention. Help of thousands of Americans.
It's called weightless,
a weight loss treatment plan that consists of three in one custom compounded
medications, diet plans,
and nutritionist support all through our digital health platform in a recent
internal patients. Do you hear this? It's, it's very similar to, you know,
your TikTok style videos, but, um, this is how you get through a, a voiceover,
a a long voiceover, any voiceover for that matter. Um,
I would highly suggest doing it like this, not in a linear format.
Now the next step is to apply, uh,
slight cross fades to your audios, uh, to your,
your voiceovers. And so, um,
I like to just highlight all of this and then hit command
or con maybe for you. Um, windows shift.
D oops. Oh, that's weird.
Oh, I think there was like a little, you can draw. Lemme see. Oh,
the shortcut isn't working here, so that's fine.
Let's, so basically I want to add a transition here.
So constant fade or constant gain in between,
there's a shortcut when you, when you highlight all of them.
And then if you hit, uh,
windows shift d d as in David,
you can automatically apply the fates to the front or to all the points.
That way it's a smoother transition each time. But for this example,
I'm gonna do them manually because, uh, I'm recording on Loom and I think the,
the, um, talk, he's,
they're conflicting, but this is gonna give you a much cleaner sound.
Okay? Uh, one thing about these and pharmacists, and it isn't a,
you don't want them too long, okay? You want them really short,
really thin pharmacy to see if otherwise they're gonna like get really quiet on
you and that's not what you want. If medically appropriate,
you can receive your me medication in the mail in as little as 48 hours.
Begin your transformation today, this medic boom. Okay?
So I don't go to the extent of like adding like EQ and stuff,
I don't think that's necessary. Um, but
I do like to add any levels. Um,
I did mention this in the previous tutorial where I will add a,
let me move this, um,
a hard limiter because I saw in the video it was actually peaking a little bit.
So you can do on each track,
I'll do audio, uh, yeah, track number one, I'll go to hard limiter,
double click on the settings and maximum amplitude,
I'm gonna do negative six. And I think that's solid.
So what that's gonna do is this medically customized meta.
I'll make sure that nothing reaches beyond negative call,
like weight loss program by new image is helping transform the health of
thousands of Americans. It's called weight lift. Okay?
So an easy way to just transfer this over hit option or alt and, um,
and now I've got it on both of my tracks.
Weight loss program by new image is helping transform the health of thousands of
Americans.
It's called weightless a weight loss treatment plan that consists of three in
one custom compounded medications, diet plans,
and nutritionist support all through our digital health. Okay?
So if I wanted to add, you know, some sort of
with noise reduction, I could do like a a d reverb as well.
There's a little bit of reverb weight loss program by new, uh, for this one now,
very light reverb reduction new image is helping transform the health of
thousands of Americans. It's called weight loss,
a weight loss treatment plan that consists of three in one custom compounded
medications, diet plans,
and nutritionist support all through our digital health platform.
In a recent internal patient survey conducted by new image patients who took
wait list loss, just kind clears out some of the extra noise.
30 days wait list is a prescription only. Wait, I'm happy with that.
Now you can see the,
the difference in length and video went from 20 seconds
here to now 40, what is it?
42 seconds. And that's not including a c t a, so maybe 44 seconds.
Um, this video is gonna be significantly longer to, to edit.
Uh, will require, require a lot more B roll as well as, um,
captions and everything else just because the, the storyline's longer.
But, um, it would basically follow the same principle from here. You know,
you just start laying over your B-roll shots, matching the,
the voiceover and follow that process. But sometimes,
you know, if, if the, the voiceover's too long to begin with, you know,
I think this is a, you could, you could potentially just do a,
a second voiceover that's 20 seconds long. That's a lot shorter,
much more straight to the point. But because this one was, uh,
run through by lawyers and whatnot,
they wanted it worded a certain way then it happened to be this long.
But if I were to do it,
I would definitely tighten it up and make it a lot shorter. Um,
you know, I'll maybe even try doing one here. Let's see,
I can do like a recording.
I lost six. Oh, it's, uh,
lemme try doing this without hearing myself.
I lost 60 pounds with weightless.
Weightless is helping transform the health of thousands of Americans includes
three blah, blah, blah, ingredients over below.
People are losing 17.8 pounds. You've gotta check this out.
It's not available at any pharmacy. Go to weightless today.
All right, that was a really bad attempt, but you get the point, right?
Something just a lot more straightforward to the point I lost 60 pounds with
weightless. Weightless is helping transform balance. Okay?
So one thing that I just wanted to explain to you when you do add a voiceover is
you wanna make sure that your,
your audio levels are balanced and your music isn't too loud.
So one,
one thing that I like to do with music as a rule of thumb is just reduce it down
to negative 10 or negative 15.
So you can hit G for gain and just do minus 15 here.
And right there, I lost 60 pounds with weightless.
Weightless is helping transform the health of thousands of merit. Okay,
so this audio is a little quiet so I can actually,
I'll hit gain again and boost it up by five.
I lost 60 pounds with weightless. Weightless is helping transform. Okay?
So obviously this isn't a perfect voiceover,
so let's not be critical of that. But, um,
same process would follow, right? I would trim, I would trim the, uh,
the gaps and I would layer them over each other.
And if you need to add another track, go ahead.
So you can do something like that where weightless,
weightless is helping transform the health of thousands of Americans.
All right? So just roll through that entire process.
Dabl ingredients over blah, blah, blah. People are losing 17.8 pounds.
You've gotta check this out. It's not available at any pharmacy.
Go to wait list today. Yeah, so
pharmacy go to wait list today. Uh, but anyways,
you can go through and then add those additional effects on there.
I believe that's A two, A three.
And the noise reduction. D noise or D reverb,
was it D reverb? Yes. Light reverb reduction.
And I lost 60 pounds of weightless.
Weightless is helping transform the health of thousands of miracles. So anyways,
I think that's a pretty straightforward voiceover tutorial. Uh,
just to reiterate, we want to go and trim
all the points so that we keep what's only necessary and then
we want to reduce all the ums or, you know, if this is a,
if this is a non voiceover script and it's a testimonial,
you're looking to cut out anything that's, uh,
that's unnecessary and that that could be a different test, uh,
that could be a different tutorial,
cutting testimonial lines. But in this case, what,
what I really wanted to show you was how to overlap these voiceovers
so that they're quick and punchy. Alright guys,
I hope that was valuable and you learned something.
I'll see you guys in the next one.